Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites
2009-ongoing
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York University
Underwood, Kent
MSS.496
688 websites in 688 archived websites.
The New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites (2014-ongoing) consists of a selection of websites produced and operated by contemporary composers for the promotion of their work and careers. The websites typically include biographical data, calendars of performances, catalogs of scores and recordings, and embedded audio and video. Capture of the sites began in 2014 and is ongoing.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Conditions Governing Access
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
Custodial History
Websites were selected by Kent Underwood and Robin Preiss and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Accession numbers associated with this collection are 2012.350, 2016.029, 2016.034, 2016.040, 2016.041, 2017.013, 2017.038, 2017.043, 2017.044, 2017.045, 2017.046, 2017.048, 2017.055, 2017.056, 2017.057, 2017.058, 2017.059, 2017.060, 2017.061, 2017.062, 2017.063, 2017.064, 2017.065, 2017.066, 2017.067, 2017.069, 2017.070, 2017.071, 2017.072, 2017.073, 2017.074, 2017.075, 2017.076, 2017.077, 2017.078, 2017.079, 2017.080, 2017.081, 2017.082, 2017.083, 2017.084, 2017.093, 2017.094. 2017.095, 2017.096, 2017.097, 2017.098, 2017.100, 2017.101, 2017.102, 2017.103, 2017.104, 2017.106, 2017.107, 2017.108, 2017.109, 2017.110, 2017.111, 2017.112, 2017.113, 2017.114, 2017.115, 2017.116, 2017.117, 2017.118, 2017.119, 2017.120, 2017.121, 2017.122, 2017.123, 2017.124, 2017.125, 2017.126, 2017.127, 2017.128, 2017.129, 2017.130, 2017.131, 2017.132, 2017.133, 2017.134, 2017.135, 2017.136, 2017.137, 2017.138, 2017.139, 2017.140, 2017.141, 2017.143, 2017.144, 2017.145, 2017.146, 2017.147, 2017.148, 2017.149, 2017.150, 2017.151, 2017.152, 2017.153, 2017.154, 2017.155, 2017.156, 2017.157, 2017.158, 2017.159, 2017.160, 2017.161, 2017.162, 2017.164, 2017.165, 2017.166, 2017.167, 2017.168, 2017.170, 2017.189, 2017.190, 2017.192, 2017.193, 2017.194, 2017.195, 2017.196, 2017.197, 2017.198, 2017.199, 2017.200, 2017.201, 2017.202, 2017.203, 2017.204, 2017.206, 2017.207, 2017.208, 2017.209, 2017.210, 2017.211, 2017.212, 2017.213, 2017.214, 2017.215, 2017.216, 2017.217, 2017.218, 2017.220, 2017.221, 2017.222, 2017.223, 2017.224, 2017.225, 2017.226, 2017.227, 2017.228, 2017.229, 2017.232, 2017.233, 2017.235, 2017.236, 2017.237, 2017.238, 2017.239, 2017.240, 2017.241, 2017.242, 2017.243, 2017.244, 2017.245, 2017.246, 2017.247, 2017.248, 2017.249, 2017.250, 2017.252, 2017.253, 2017.254, 2017.255, 2017.256, 2017.257, 2017.258, 2017.259, 2017.260, 2017.261, 2017.262, 2017.263, 2017.264, 2017.265, 2017.266, 2017.267, 2017.268, 2017.269, 2017.270, 2017.271, 2017.272, 2017.273, 2017.274, 2017.275, 2017.276, 2017.277, 2017.278, 2017.279, 2017.280, 2017.281, 2017.282, 2017.283, 2017.284, 2017.285, 2017.287, 2017.288, 2017.289, 2017.290, 2017.292, 2017.293, 2017.294, 2017.295, 2017.296, 2017.297, 2017.298, 2018.001, 2018.002, 2018.003, 2018.004, 2018.005, 2018.006, 2018.007, 2018.008, 2018.009, 2018.010, 2018.011, 2018.012, 2018.013, 2018.014, 2018.015, 2018.016, 2018.017, 2018.018, 2018.019, 2018.020, 2018.021, 2018.022, 2018.023, 2019.067, 2019.069, 2019.072, 2019.073, 2020.007, 2020.010, 2020.012, 2020.014, 2020.015, 2020.018, 2020.026, 2020.029, 2020.030, 2020.038, 2021.002, 2021.007, 2021.008, 2021.019, 2021.032, 2021.038, 2022.006, 2022.007, 2022.008, 2022.010, 2022.013, 2022.019, 2022.024, 2022.028, 2022.032, 2022.034, 2022.036, 2022.041, 2022.043, 2022.045, 2022.049, 2023.001, 2023.002, 2023.013, 2023.022, 2023.028, 2023.034, 2023.041, 2023.045, 2024.002, 2024.012, 2024.026, 2024.030, 2024.037, 2025.004, 2025.007, 2025.010, 2025.015, 2025.020.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes JavaScript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Accruals
As of 2021, websites are captured annually.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by last name of the composer.
Scope and Contents
The New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites (2014-ongoing) consists of a selection of websites produced and operated by contemporary composers for the promotion of their work and careers. "Contemporary" is defined as living or, in a few cases, very recently deceased. "Composers" is defined as creative musicians who are working within, are descending from, or are in some significant way connected to the Western traditions of concert music; this includes composers who produce notated scores plus those whose work embraces improvisation, collaborative composition, and other post-modern/post-classical creative practices. The sites typically include biographical data; calendars of performances; catalogs of scores and recordings; and embedded audio and video. Capture of the sites began in 2014 and is ongoing.
Historical Note
The New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites (2014-ongoing) was established in 2014 as part of a grant from the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation. The curatorial emphasis was on young, emerging American composers. New composers were selected by curators Kent Underwood and Robin Preiss from 2015-2018.
Composers -- United States -- 21st century; Web sites.; Music festivals.; Underwood, Kent
- Adamo, Mark, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Scope and Contents
  The website contains descriptions of the composer's compositions. It also has a biography of the artist, links to reviews of his works, examples of prose pieces written by Adamo, and information about which of his works are currently in print. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of markadamo.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Biographical Note
  Mark Adamo (b. 1962) is a composer and librettist of music for opera. His pieces also include chamber, symphonic, and coral compositions. His operas include Little Women (1998), Lysistrata (2005), The Gospel of Mary Magdalene (2011), The Lord of Cries (2021), where he was the librettist, and Becoming Santa Claus (2015).
- Adams, Samuel Carl, February 2015-ongoing; Adams, Samuel Carl, 1985-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of samuelcarladams.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Samuel Adams (b. 1985) is an American composer who combines acoustic and digital sound. His repertoire includes works for orchestra, large ensemble, small ensemble, and piano. He also creates multimedia and collaborative works. His orchestral piece No Such Spring, which premiered in 2023, received widespread acclaim. It was composed for pianist Conor Hanick and conductor Esa-Pekka Slonen of the San Francisco Symphony. Adams was involved in the establishment of the Civic Orchestra New Music Workshop with the Negaunee Institute of Music, a program for emerging composers.
  The website contains a list of upcoming events, news, a biography, contact information, and a list of works.
- Adès, Thomas, April 2014-ongoing; Adès, Thomas; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of thomasades.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Robots.txt was ignored.
  Thomas Adès (b. 1971) is a British performer and composer of opera, orchestra, chamber, and solo works. Adès is the author of three operas: The Exterminating Angel, The Tempest, and Powder Her Face. His orchestral works include the titles Asyla, Tevot, In Seven Days, and Totentanz.
  The website contains compositions, recordings, a biography, performances, and contact information. This description is based on the February 2023 crawl.
- Adler, Christopher, August 2011- ongoing; cuid5909; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of christopheradler.com and adlerforum.blogspot.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  adlerforum.blogspot.com, an external site, was included due to its contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of Adler; a list of his compositions with descriptions of the works; a calendar of his events; a list of recordings; information about his new music solo and ensemble works for the khaen; a list of writings; a store with his scores; and contact information.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SoundCloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Christopher Adler (b. 1972) is a contemporary composer, performer, and improviser. His works draw on the traditional music of Laos and Thailand as well as his interest in mathematics and 20th century Russian futurism to form cross-cultural hybrid concert pieces. He is best known for his work with the khaen, a traditional instrument from southeast Asia. Some of Adler's notable works include the chamber oratorio, Aeneas in the Underworld; a piece for two pianos titled Science Fictions, which is based on mathematical sequences; and Zaum Box, a collection of ten movements for speaking percussionist. Adler is also an accomplished pianist, a Professor of Music, and Director of the Asian Studies Program at the University of San Diego.
- Aftab, Arooj, April 2014-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of aroojaftab.com, aroojaftab.bandcamp.com, and aroojaftabmusic.com, in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains information about Aftab's compositions and projects; liner notes written by writer and sound practitioner Lynnée Denise; a discography of Aftab's published albums; and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files. It also includes a store; contact information; and calendar of tour dates. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description was updated in March 2025. The website also includes the artist's Bandcamp page.
  Embedded Bandcamp audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Arooj Aftab (b. 1985) is a composer of classically inspired experimental acoustic and electronic ambient music that incorporates elements of jazz, South Asian classical music, pop, and blues. Aftab employs a variety of techniques in her compositions, including music production, sound engineering, and vocal practice. Notable titles of her authorship include Night Reign and Love in Exile, which she co-created with Vijay Iyer and Shahzad Ismaily.
- Agócs, Kati, April 2014-ongoing; Agócs, Kati; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of agocsmusic.com and katiagocs.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Kati Agócs (b. 1975) is a Canadian-born composer and vocalist of Hungarian and American descent. Her repertoire includes works for orchestra and chamber music. Recent works by Agócs include Hosanna of the Clouds, Transluminescence, Horn Concerto, and Voices for the Immaculate.
  www.agocsmusic.com was first crawled in 2015 and the website contained a biography, news announcements, a list of works, information on performances, press information, CDs, contact information, and blog posts. As of 2023, this website no longer exists in the live web. As of March 2025, the composer's website changed URLs to www.katiagocs.com. It contains a biography of the artist; news; calendar of past and upcoming events; examples of her pieces in the form of embedded audio files; list of Agócs' works accompanied by scores; press reviews; her blog where she writes about topics related to her professional and personal life; and contact information.
- Akiho, Andy, February 2014-ongoing; cuid5897
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of andyakiho.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of articles by the press regarding Akiho's work, images of the artist, videos of his compositions, a discography of his published albums, a calendar of upcoming performances, a list of scores, and contact information. Capture of site began in February 2014. This description was updated in February 2025.
  Parts of the live site involving YouTube were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Andy Akiho (b. 1979) is a composer of contemporary classical music who plays the steel pan and steel piano. Akiho is a Pulitzer Prize finalist and received seven Grammy nominations. Notable works composed by Akiho include Nisei, a cello concerto; Sculptures, which was composed as a symphonic piece; and BeLonging, composed for wind instruments.
- Aldridge, Robert Livingstone, August 2015-ongoing; Aldridge, Robert Livingston, 1954-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist, a list with descriptions of his compositions, a list of recordings, press features, a calendar of events, a list of links to external websites, and contact information.
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of robertlivingstonaldridge.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Robert Livingstone Aldridge (b. 1954) is a contemporary composer of mostly instrumental pieces. His compositions include works for orchestra, opera, music-theater, voice, dance, string quartet, solo, and classical ensembles. Aldridge was a founder of the Composers in Red Sneakers, an internationally recognized composer consortium. He is the composer of the opera Elmer Gantry, based on the novel by Sinclair Lewis, with libretto by Herschel Garfein. The opera was released as a CD by the record label Naxos, and received two Grammy Awards in 2012 for Best Contemporary Classical Composition and Best Engineered Classical Recording.
- Alessi, Ralph, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ralphalessi.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Ralph Alessi (b. 1963) is a jazz trumpet player, composer, ECM recording artist, and educator. He is a member of the Alessi, Black, Ducret Trio, and also performs in a quartet with Matt Mitchell, John Hebert, and Ches Smith. As an educator, he has taught improvisation, composition, and trumpet, and is the founder and director of the School for Improvisational Music in Brooklyn, New York.
  The website contains a biography, teaching information, videos, a list of upcoming performances, a discography, and descriptions of current projects. This description is based off of the February 2023 crawl.
- Alexander, Elizabeth, April 2014-ongoing; Alexander, Elizabeth, 1962 August 6-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of seafarerpress.com and elizabethalexander.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains the composer's music. It also includes sheet music for purchase, reviews, commissions, Alexander's biographies, a complete catalog of her works, videos of performances of her works, and journal entries. As of March 2025, the website also contains a section dedicated to the creation of her musical Split Hickory, which is a work in progress.
  Elizabeth Alexander (b. 1962) is a Minnesota-based composer who focuses on orchestral, chamber, piano, and vocal works, often liturgical in nature. One of Alexander's latest works is the musical Split Hickory, which is set in Central Appalachia, where she grew up. The musical features Alexander's original folk-country music.
  Custodial History
  The website was initially captured under the URL https://www.seafarerpress.com until 2018, when it redirected to http://elizabethalexander.com.
- Alexander, Kathryn, August 2015-June 2019; Alexander, Kathryn, 1955-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  The website contained descriptions of the artist's compositions; a biography; lists of her recognitions; talks and prose writings; calendar of her events; and a catalog of her musical works with embedded audio examples. As of 2024 the website no longer exists online.
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of kathrynalexander.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded audio was broken in the live site as well as the site capture.
  Kathryn Alexander (b. 1955) is a composer of instrumental pieces for ensembles using traditional and technological instruments. She is also a Professor of Composition at New York University. Alexander's work draws on literature, visual arts, science, and technology. Her pieces include music for solo, chamber ensemble, voice, and orchestral music, as well as multimedia works. Some titles by Alexander include AroundAbout; In the Purest Air, Sapphirine; Dreams and Reveries; and The Faraway Nearby.
- Alves, Bill, February 2015-ongoing; cuid5908; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.billalves.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography; a list with information about the artist's works; examples of his compositions in the form of embedded audio and video files; a catalog of his recordings; a bibliography of Alves' writings; and contact information.
  Soundcloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Bill Alves (b. 1960) is a composer, writer, and video artist based in Southern California. who creates music for traditional acoustic instruments from around the world, in particular Indonesian gamelan, and electronic media. Examples of musical releases by Alves include The Terrain of Possibilities, Imbal-Imbalan, Mystic Canyon, and Guitars and Gamelan. Alves is also the author of books such as Music of the Peoples of the World and Lou Harrison: American Musical Maverick, a biography that he co-authored with Brett Campbell. Alves is also the director of the Harvey Mudd College American Gamelan ensemble, which plays non-traditional music with specially tuned Javanese instruments.
- Ames, Charles, April 2014-ongoing; cuid5857; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of charlesames.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of Ames, a list of his works, descriptions of how he makes his music, and links to his publications. Capture of the site began in December 2016. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
  Charles Ames is a composer with a background in mathematics and programming, which he employs to create music using a combination of computers and traditional instruments. His compositions include Peripheries, Crystals, Protocol, Gradient, Undulant, 11 Demonstrations, Excursion, Artifacts, Maze, and Concurrence.
- Amram, David, August 2011-December 2019; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  The website was made up of descriptions of his compositions; biography of the artist; links to reviews of his works; calendar of Amram's events; and links to videos of performances of his works. As of April 2025, the blog was made private and is only open to invited readers.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of david-amram.blogspot.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  David Werner Amram III (b. 1930) is a composer of chamber, orchestral, choral music, and operas. Amram's career spans over 50 decades. Some examples of notable moments in his career include the creation and performance of the first ever Jazz and Poetry readings in New York City with novelist Jack Kerouac in 1957; the music direction of the Lincoln Center Theater from 1964 to 1966; and his appointment as the first Composer-In-Residence for the New York Philharmonic in 1966. His personal and professional papers are housed at the Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts branch of the New York Public Library.
- Andel, Laura, February 2015-ongoing; Andel, Laura, 1968-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of lauraandel.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Laura Andel (b. 1968) is an Argentine musician, conductor, composer, and sound artist based in Harlem, New York. Her creative practice focuses on sound, music drawing, instrument building, installation, and performance. Her compositions combine written music with improvisation, and span a variety of genres and instruments from different parts of the world. Ansel also builds her own instruments in clay. Examples of such creations include seashell-shaped trumpets that she employs on electroacoustic pieces.
  As of April 2025, the website contains news; biography; her CV; information about her collaborations with other musicians; press reviews; a list of projects; a list of works; visual arts including her music drawings and collages; teaching information; and contact information.
- Anderson, Beth, August 2009-February 2019; Anderson, Beth, 1950-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of beand.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.